Felix Andrade May

 \cdot (+44) 07857830805 · f.andrademay@gmail.com · felixam.dev · linkedin.com/in/felixAmay · Flat 3, 4 South Marine Terrace, Aberystwyth, SY23 1JX ·

Profile

I am a graduate from Aberystwyth University with a First Class Honours B.Sc in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence. For my dissertation I researched the performance of existing machine learning techniques for the prediction of phenotypes from genotypes in plants. I have learned a proficiency in Java through extensive use during my education and I have experience developing commercial programs in Python and C++ in a professional environment. Through prior work and education I have acquired a strong and robust experience with source control processes and agile methodologies in the workplace.

Education

Aberystwyth University

2020 - 2024

• Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, B.Sc First Class Honours

Ivybridge Community College 6th Form

2017 - 2019

• A-Levels in Computer Science (B), Geography (C), and Physics (E)

Employment

Software Engineer - Intern, RTX

August 2022 – August 2023

- Collaborated remotely and in-person with a cross-functional team of engineers to develop a diverse range of commercial products.
- Managed three core back-end services written in C++ and containerized with Docker, ensuring their reliability and up-to-date functionality for their utilisation by multiple products.
- Developed REST API functions for web applications built with HTML, JavaScript, and EmberJS.
- Co-developed features for experimental software with the IRAD department, showcasing solutions to internal customers.
- Expanded my debugging and problem solving skills while working with third-party open-source libraries causing critical errors in core pipelines.
- Designed and developed UI elements and data-processing algorithms in Python for aiding in the generation and viewing of digital elevation models (DEMs).
- Wrote detailed and communicative documentation for back-end services, facilitating knowledge transfer for future developers and users.
- Investigated, designed, prototyped, and implemented a new feature and API hook for one of the backend services.
- Collaborated with the product owner to investigate, debug, and improve efficiency in an existing codebase, helping to reduce the request time for a new feature from 20 seconds to less than half a second.

Community Tester, Offworld Industries

July 2021 – August 2024

- Worked alongside developers and community testers to identify bugs and weaknesses in test builds.
- Improved communication skills by relaying bugs and feedback to the community and the development team.
- Expanded my ability to present and discuss technical concepts to a wide range of audiences.

Skills and Achievements

Technical Skills

Python

- 10 years of experience creating both professional and scientific programs.
- Developed genetic analysis programs for evaluating DNA samples collected from cattle rumen.

Felix Andrade May

- Developed a suite of machine learning models and auxiliary files for the prediction of phenotypes from genotypes in plants as part of my dissertation work.
- Extensive professional experience in processing aerial images, creating tiled images, digital elevation models (DEMs), and stereo images.
- Helped develop machine learning models to detect changes in aerial images.
- Developed a pipeline for the pre-processing of open-source elevation data for the creation of DEMs.

Web Development

- Designed and developed a personal website using NextJS and Typescript.
- Experience working on legacy websites using Javascript and EmberJS.
- Experience with modern frameworks like NextJS and React.

RESTful Services

- Developed RESTful hooks for mock testing in a RTX project.
- Collaborated with a colleague to design, implement, and test new features and APIs.

Docker

- Developed and updated Docker containers for backend services and testing-and-development environments at RTX.
- Designed and developed Docker containers to develop, test, and evaluate machine learning models during my dissertation.

Backend and API Development

- Developed and maintained core backend services used by multiple products at RTX.
- Designed and implemented backend API features to support new product functionality, with a focus on efficiency and speed.

Git and Version Control

- Proficient in Git and with GitHub, GitLab, and BitBucket for project hosting and management.
- Skilled and considerate with version control practices for personal, educational, and professional projects.

Communication and Professional Skills

Remote Agile Development

- Worked remotely within an Agile team during industrial placement at RTX, improving time management and project planning.
- Independently developed an Agile rulebook to manage my dissertation project.

Communication

- Strong written and verbal communication skills, developed through academic and professional experiences.
- Skilled in explaining complex technical concepts and biological research clearly for diverse audiences.

Interests

I love discovering; during the 2021 summer I spent 2 weeks cycling 750km through northern France taking as many back roads and talking to whoever could understand my limited French. Living and studying in Wales, I have taken a keen interest in learning and expanding my Welsh language skills. I have also become interested in biotechnology and how we, as computer scientists and software developers, can help inform views on biological processes.

References